insidehighered.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy | Inside Higher Ed

_Inside Higher Ed_ values your privacy and promises to protect your personally identifiable information. The privacy policy below applies to all _Inside Higher Ed_ sites and services. Some third-party service providers used by _Inside Higher Ed_ may have their own privacy policies, and _Inside Higher Ed_ is not responsible for their privacy policies or any other practices of these sites, it is always our intention to work with reputable providers who maintain views similar to ours regarding privacy. Below, we’ll detail the ways in which we may collect information about you and how that information is handled.

**By continuing to utilize _Inside Higher Ed_ sites or services or by submitting personal information to us, you are agreeing to the terms of this privacy policy and acknowledge that your information will be handled in accordance with this policy.**

_**Information You Provide to Us**_

_Account Creation_  
You only need to provide an email address to subscribe to _Inside Higher Ed_ (create an “Account”). You have the option to provide additional data, such as your name, job title, organization, or geographic location, but you are not required to do so to receive email newsletters from us.

_Other Information You Provide_  
If you are making a purchase or otherwise entering information on our site (including to apply to a job, comment on an article, or access specific content such as a booklet/survey or webcast), we may require information to help process your transaction. This might include but is not limited to: your name, email address, job title, organization, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other information to help facilitate your experience or purchase. The only time we will ask for credit card information is when you are making a purchase on our site.

From time to time, _Inside Higher Ed_ collects data from users via surveys or other forms of market research. This data may be shared with third parties, such as advertisers, but is done so in aggregate. The only time you will need to provide personally identifiable information is if you wish to enter a contest associated with a particular survey; in those cases, you will need to provide an email address, so we can contact you about your prize. Participation in any survey is completely voluntary.

_Information You Authorize From Third-Party Services_  
We offer users the ability to create or access their _Inside Higher Ed_ account via social login. This allows you to use an existing social networking account (such as LinkedIn, Facebook or Twitter) in order to login to our site (this may be done in addition to or instead of creating an account on our site). If you choose to utilize social login, we may receive information about you from the social networking provider. For example, if you login using Facebook, Facebook may provide information such as your name, email address, public profile photo and gender. If you do not wish to share the information your social login provides, you can disconnect that login from your _Inside Higher Ed_ account.

_**Information We Collect About You**_

_Non-Identifiable Information  
Inside Higher Ed_ uses third-party analytics providers, such as Google Analytics and Chartbeat, to monitor and analyze site traffic. Our systems collect basic information about your computer, including IP address, location, operating system or browser. We also collect information about the content and services our users access on the site, including the pages they visit and the duration of use. We use this information to help us understand the needs and preferences of the _Inside Higher Ed_ audience as a whole. This information is not used to identify any specific user or track a specific user’s behavior on the site. Our systems also collect information from cookies, web beacons and similar technologies. To read more about our use of these technologies, please see the “Use of Cookies” section.

_Other Information  
Inside Higher Ed_ may also use publicly available information from third party services to improve the data we have about our users.

**_How We Use Your Information_**

We may use your information in one or more of the following ways:

_Provide the information or services you requested_ : This may include, but is not limited to, sending you electronic newsletters, sending you job alerts, processing your registration for a webcast or event, or enabling you to comment on an article.

_To communicate with you_ : We use your information to send you customer service or transactional emails. These may include, but are not limited to, communications regarding the status of your job posting, reminders about events for which you registered, replies to your email or phone inquiries, emails containing resources you requested or purchase confirmations.

_Provide information, services or advertising based on your information or preferences_ : We may use your information to inform you about resources that may be of interest to you. For example, if you subscribe to our “Admissions Insider” newsletter, we may send you an invitation to a webcast on our annual “Survey of College and University Admissions Directors.” These other messages may include marketing messages from _Inside Higher Ed_ partners. You have the right to opt out of getting those messages while still getting content from _Inside Higher Ed_. If you do not wish to receive these messages, click the “Manage Subscription Preferences” link in your email and uncheck the box(es) designating “ _Inside Higher Ed_ Resources & Events” and/or “Partner Resources & Events.” Please note that these selections are not permanent; they may be changed in the event you register for other products or services and consent to receive marketing messages. You may also email us at [publishing@insidehighered.com](mailto:publishing@insidehighered.com) for assistance.

_Conduct statistical analysis of our website(s)_ : The information we collect is used to analyze and ultimately improve our sites and services to better serve our users.

_Other uses with your consent_ : There may be other instances not included here where we may use or collect your information. Such instances will only be at your direction and/or with your consent.

**_Information Sharing With Third Parties_**

_At Your Direction or With Your Consent_  
We may share your information with third-parties when you have told us to do so or have consented to us doing so. These cases may include, but are not limited to:

  * Applying to a job: If you are applying for a job through our site, your name and email address, as well as the resume, cover letter and supporting documents that you provide with the application, will be shared with the employer.   
 
  * Creating a searchable jobseeker profile: If you choose to create and share a searchable jobseeker profile, it may be viewed by employers who are searching for candidates. You can opt-out of the jobseeker profile search database or you can block specific employers from viewing your profile.  
 
  * Accessing specific content and/or registering for an event: In some cases, we may ask for your information to facilitate the access of site content or to register for an event. This content and/or event is made possible in part by the support of a sponsor(s) and the information you provide will be shared with the sponsors(s) stated on the download or registration form. For example, if you register for a webcast sponsored by a particular company, your information may be shared with that company and also used internally for marketing purposes. The download or registration form will clearly state that your information will be shared and will require your consent to this sharing before you can access the resources or register for the event. _Inside Higher Ed_ is not responsible for the marketing or privacy practices of sponsors or business partners.

_Provide the Information or Services You Requested  
Inside Higher Ed_ uses third parties for services and functions such as managing user accounts, sending email newsletters and processing payments. Your information may be shared with the third-party services who are responsible for processing or facilitating these services on our behalf, including, but not limited to, third-party authentication, email or newsletter distribution, or data service providers and subcontractors. For example, _Inside Higher Ed_ Careers is powered by the Madgex Job Board Platform; if you post a job to or apply for a job through _Inside Higher Ed_ Careers, your information will be shared with and handled by Madgex. Likewise, when purchasing a product or service from us, your payment information will be shared with the third-party company that is responsible for processing financial transactions for _Inside Higher Ed_.  

_As Required by Law or as Needed to Protect Our Users, Sites or Services   _  
We may be bound to disclose your personal data to authorities to whom it must be disclosed in order to comply with legal, regulatory, judicial or any other request coming from an authority with jurisdiction to require the disclosure.

**_Use of Cookies_**

To enhance your experience on our Services, we may place "cookies" on your computer or device. Cookies are small text files that store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personal information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, creating an account. Once you choose to provide us with your personal information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. A cookie assigns a unique numerical identifier to your Web browser or device and may enable us to recognize you as the same user who has used our services and relate your use of the Services to other information about you, such as your usage information and personal information.

We use cookies (including, but not limited to cache cookies, web beacons or clear gifs) to understand usage of the Services and to improve our content and offerings and to deliver advertisements that you might be interested in. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience on our Services (e.g., to recognize you by name when you return to our site, to save your password in password-protected areas, to enable shopping carts, or to tailor content or product and service offerings).

You can modify your cookie preferences via your browser if you wish to change how your computer accepts cookies. You also can disable cookies altogether. However, if you disable browser cookies, it may interfere with the proper functioning of _Inside Higher Ed_ sites or services.

**_Policy Regarding Children_**

_Inside Higher Ed_ ’s sites and services are not directed to children and children are not eligible to use our sites or services. We do not knowingly collect or store any personal information about children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us, we will delete that information from our records to the fullest extent possible.

**_Your Right to Information_**

We give you the ability to manage your settings and preferences, including the ability to modify or remove your personal information. You can also ask that we correct or delete your data, if so justified. We protect your right to information by answering your questions concerning the processing of your data and respecting your right to access to your account settings, payment information or other information resulting from your use of _Inside Higher Ed_ sites and services. Persons in certain jurisdictions, including those in European Union (EU) member states, may have additional legal rights and protections and we are committed to complying with those rights and protections. To exercise your right to your information under applicable law, please email us at [privacy@insidehighered.com](mailto:privacy@insidehighered.com).

**_How We Retain Your Data_**

We keep your account data for as long as it is needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected, to provide our services, to deal with possible legal claims, to comply with our business interests and/or to abide by all applicable laws. Thereafter, we either delete your personal data or de-identify it. We delete jobseeker and subscriber accounts that have been inactive for at least three years. Please note that even if you request the deletion of your data, we may be required (by law or otherwise) to retain the data and not delete it. However, once those requirements are removed, we will delete your data in accordance with your request.

**_How We Protect the Security of Your Data_**

We have put in place appropriate organizational, technical and physical safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security and correctly use the information we collect. We work to protect the security of your information notably during transmission, using HTTPS to encrypt any data you provide via our sites and services. However, no manner of data storage or transmission is completely secure. It is also important for you to protect your data, especially to prevent unauthorized access to your password and to your computer.

**_Contact Us_**

If you have additional questions regarding this privacy policy, if you would like to opt-out of receiving communications from us, or if you want to lodge a complaint with us, please email us at [privacy@insidehighered.com](mailto:privacy@insidehighered.com).

_**Dispute Resolution**_

EU residents may report privacy complaints directly to their local data protection authorities. You may also contact us to be directed to the relevant authorities.

**_Changes to Our Privacy Policy_**

We review this privacy policy regularly and may modify or otherwise update it at any time. The current version in effect will be available on our website at <https://www.insidehighered.com/content/privacy>. We encourage you to review this policy from time to time to understand how your data is collected and used.

Last Updated: 5-23-2018
